hi again folks so let's talk a little
大家好，再说一遍
bit about a folk theorem now for a
现在谈谈一个民间定理
discounted repeated game so we're in the
打折重复游戏，所以我们在
case where there's a discount factor and
有折扣因素的情况下
people care more about today than the
人们比今天更关心
future or tomorrow and so forth and we
未来或明天等等，我们
want to think about the expansion of the
想考虑的扩展
logic that we just went through and some
我们刚刚经历的逻辑和一些
examples but see whether that holds in a
例子，但看看是否在
general setting of repeated games so
重复游戏的一般设置
what's the folk theorem what's the
民间定理是什么
extension to repeated games so take a
扩展到重复游戏，因此
normal forma game and so there's
正常的形式游戏，所以有
actually very many versions of folk
其实民间的版本很多
theorems and we'll do a very particular
定理，我们将做一个非常特别的
one which has I think the basic
我认为基本的
intuition behind it and a fairly simple
背后的直觉和相当简单
proof so the idea is is we're looking at
证明，所以我们的想法是
some Nash equilibrium of the stage game
阶段游戏的纳什均衡
so take a stage game find a profile
所以参加一个舞台游戏找到一个个人资料
which is a Nash equilibrium of the stage
这是阶段的纳什均衡
game and then also look for some
游戏，然后还寻找一些
alternative strategy and here we have a
另类策略，在这里我们有一个
couple of typos that should be in a
错别字应该在
prime so look for some alternative
总理，所以寻找一些替代方案
strategy a prime such that everybody
策略素数，使每个人
gets a strictly higher payoff from a
从中获得更高的收益
prime than a ok where a is the Nash
优胜于OK，那是纳什
equilibrium then there exists some
平衡，然后存在一些
discount factor below one such that if
低于1的折现系数，如果
everybody has a discount factor above
每个人都有一个以上的折扣系数
that level then there exists a sub-game
那个水平，然后有一个子游戏
perfect equilibrium of the infinite
无限的完美平衡
repetition of the game that has a prime
具有质数的游戏的重复
played in every period on the
在每个时期都玩过
equilibrium path so what this is telling
平衡路径，这说明了什么
us is the logic that we went through in
我们是我们经历的逻辑
those two examples of prisoners dilemmas
那两个囚徒困境的例子
where we found the discount factory
我们找到折扣工厂的地方
there half or at least 7 9 etc take any
有一半或至少7 9等采取任何
game find a Nash equilibrium of that and
游戏找到那个的纳什均衡
find something which is better than that
找到比这更好的东西
which you'd like to sustain in an
您想维持在
infinitely repeated game and you can do
无限重复的游戏，你可以做
the same logic that we did in those
与我们在那些逻辑中所做的相同的逻辑
examples in the general case where
一般情况下的例子
there'll be a high enough discount
会有足够高的折扣
factor that'll make that sustainable ok
使可持续发展的因素
and and basically the proof of this
并基本上证明了这一点
theorem is is very similar to what we
定理与我们非常相似
went through in those examples so the
经历了那些例子，所以
idea is is you know we'll play a prime
想法是你知道我们会发挥主要作用
as long as everybody plays it
只要大家玩
if anybody deviates from that then we're
如果有人偏离了那我们
gonna go to a grim trigger we're just
要去一个严峻的触发，我们只是
gonna threaten to play the Nash
威胁要打纳什
equilibrium a forever after which is
永远平衡之后
giving us a lower payoff than a prime
给我们的回报比素数低
and we just need to make sure that
我们只需要确保
people care enough about the loss of the
人们足够在意损失
future to offset the game the game from
未来来抵消游戏
today so in terms of the the proof
今天，就证明而言
checking that this is a sub-game
检查这是一个子游戏
equilibrium for high enough discount
足够高的折扣的均衡
factors what do we have to do well
因素我们要做好什么
playing a forever if everyone anyone is
如果每个人都在玩一个永远
ever deviated is part of a sub-game
曾经偏离的游戏是子游戏的一部分
perfect continuation if we ever have a
如果我们有一个完美的延续
deviation because it's Nash in every sub
偏差，因为它是每个子项中的纳什
game so we need to check will anybody
游戏，所以我们需要检查任何人
want to deviate from a prime if nobody
如果没有人想偏离素数
has in the past and we can bound the
在过去，我们可以绑定
game so an upper bound on the gain is
游戏，所以收益的上限是
the maximum over all players and all
所有玩家和所有玩家的最大值
possible deviations they could have of
他们可能会有的偏差
the best of the gain and payoff that
最好的收益和回报
they would get from that so that gives
他们会从中得到，所以给
us a maximum possible gain the minimum
我们最大可能获得最小
period per period loss so this is the
每个时期的损失，所以这是
maximum they can gain from today well
他们今天最大的收获就是
compared to the minimum they could lose
与他们可能损失的最低赔率相比
from tomorrow
从明天起
so the minimum they could lose is
因此他们可能损失的最低金额是
instead of getting a prime they're not
而不是得到一个素数，他们不是
going to go to a so that's that and and
去一个就是这样，并且
take that the minimum across different
把不同的最小值
players for this and one question is
玩家对此，一个问题是
sort of why this the question here is
有点为什么这是这里的问题
you know is really the minimum relative
你知道真的是最小的亲戚
to the Nash equilibrium or could they
到纳什均衡还是
gain so think about this a little bit
获得，所以请对此一点点思考
why wouldn't they want to change from
他们为什么不想要从
the Nash equilibrium in the future right
未来权利中的纳什均衡
so the idea there is there they're not
所以那里没有他们的想法
going to be able to to help themselves
能够自助
by trying to change away from the
通过尝试改变
punishment because that is a Nash
惩罚，因为那是纳什
equilibrium so they're already getting
平衡，所以他们已经在
the best possible payoff if the other
最好的回报，如果其他
people follow through with the
人们遵循
punishment so we've got the maximum
惩罚，所以我们得到了最大的
possible game the minimum possible loss
可能的游戏最小可能的损失
so if I deviate and given what other
所以如果我偏离并给了其他
players are doing the maximum possible
玩家正在尽最大努力
net gain overall is our gain the M today
总体净收益是我们今天的收益M
but I could lose up to M tomorrow
但明天我可能输给M
in the future I'll lose at least them in
将来我至少会失去他们
the future and this should be an AI then
未来，这应该是一个人工智能
we've got beta I over 1 minus beta I and
我们的Beta I超过1减去Beta I，并且
so if you go ahead and you know set this
因此，如果您继续进行，并且知道设置
has to be non-negative sorry has to be
必须是非负的，对不起
negative in order for players not to
消极的，以使球员不
want to deviate so what do we need we
想偏离，所以我们需要什么
need that M is less than or equal to
需要M小于或等于
this so M over m is less than or equal
因此，M大于m小于或等于
to beta I over 1 minus beta I and that
超过1的beta I减去beta I，
gives us a lower bound on beta I it has
给了我们它的beta的下限
to be at least M over m plus m so that's
至少M超过m加m，所以
a not a tight lower bound in the sense
从某种意义上讲不是一个严格的下限
that we went with fairly loose bounds
我们的界限相当宽松
here but if everybody has a high enough
在这里，但如果每个人都足够高
discount factor then you can sustain
折扣系数，那么您可以维持
cooperation so this is just a
合作，所以这只是一个
straightforward generalization of the
的直接概括
examples we looked through before and
我们之前看过的例子
it's showing us that we can sustain
告诉我们我们可以维持
cooperation in an infinitely repeated
合作无限重复
setting this is provided people have
设置这个是提供给人们
enough patience for the future now
现在对未来有足够的耐心
there's many bells and whistles on this
有很多风吹草动
one thing to think about you could you
想一想你能
can sustain fairly complicated play if
可以维持相当复杂的比赛，如果
you if you'd like so let's take a look
如果您愿意的话，让我们看一下
at the game we looked at before so the
在我们之前看过的游戏中，
prisoner's dilemma but now we've got
囚徒的困境，但现在我们有了
this very high payoff from deviating one
从偏离中获得很高的回报
thing you can notice is the total of the
您可以注意到的是
payoffs here the players together get
玩家们在这里得到的回报
ten if they cooperate they're only
十，如果他们合作，他们只是
getting six in total so here actually
一共六个
playing this makes one of the players
玩这个使球员之一
really well off so if they played this
真的很好，所以如果他们玩这个
in perpetuity they get three three
他们永远得到三三
suppose they trying to do following they
假设他们试图跟随他们
say in odd periods we'll play a CD right
说在奇怪的时期我们会播放CD权利
so in in periods one three five and so
所以在一期三五等
forth will play cooperate by the first
第四将发挥合作的第一
player defect for the other so the
另一个玩家的缺陷
second player is going to get tens in
第二个玩家将获得
those periods but then we'll play will
那些时期，但是我们将演奏
reverse it and the even periods
扭转它和偶数期
right so now roughly on average players
现在大概是普通玩家
are getting five each instead of three
每人得到五个而不是三个
each right so what we'll do is what
每一项权利，所以我们要做的是
we'll alternate and as long as we're
我们会交替，只要我们
you're continuing to abide by these
你继续遵守这些
rules where we nicely do this then in in
规定我们在哪里做的很好
the future as long as everybody does
只要每个人都做的未来
this we'll continue to do it
这我们会继续做
if anybody deviates from this then we'll
如果有人偏离这一点，那么我们将
just go to defect defect right and you
只是去缺陷缺陷吧，你
can check and see what kinds of discount
可以检查看看有哪些折扣
factors you need and you know are there
你需要的因素，你知道在那里
different discount factors you need for
您需要的不同折扣系数
the first player that the player is
该玩家是的第一个玩家
getting the CD in the first period
在第一期获得CD
versus the second player and so forth
与第二个玩家等
you can go through that and actually
你可以经历一下，实际上
this kind of thing is is something that
这种事情是
people worry about in regulatory
人们担心监管
settings so for instance you know
设置，例如，您知道
imagine that you have a situation where
想象你有一种情况
you've got companies bidding for
你有公司竞标
government contracts and they're
政府合同，他们是
repeating you know they're doing this
再说一遍，你知道他们正在这样做
repeatedly over time and one way they
随着时间的推移反复出现，一种方法是
could do it is to say okay look we can
可以说是可以的，我们可以
compete against each other and bid very
互相竞争并非常出价
high every day or have to bid you know
每天都很高，或者必须出价
to give them a the government of low
给他们一个低下的政府
cost every day if there's a procurement
如果有采购，每天都会花费
contract but what they could do
合同，但他们能做什么
alternatively is say okay look I'll let
或者说好吧，我会让
you in the contract today you let me win
你今天的合同，你让我赢
it tomorrow and we'll just alternate and
明天，我们将轮流和
as long as we keep cooperating we won't
只要我们保持合作，我们就不会
compete with each other we'll enjoy high
相互竞争，我们将享受高
payoffs but if that ever breaks down
回报，但如果失败了
then we're gonna go back to competition
然后我们要回到竞争
so there's situations where regulators
因此，在某些情况下，监管机构
worry and in fact there's some various
担心，实际上有一些
cases that have some evidence that
有证据表明
companies will tend to do this to try
公司将倾向于这样做尝试
and game the system and an increase
和游戏系统，并增加
payoff so so you can see that the kind
回报，所以你可以看到那种
of logic and what has to be true in
逻辑和什么必须是真实的
order for that to happen
为了做到这一点
okay so repeated games we've had a
好吧，如此反复的比赛，我们有一个
fairly detailed look at these things
比较详细地看这些东西
players can condition their future play
玩家可以限制他们未来的比赛
on past actions that allows them to
根据他们过去的行动
react to things in ways that they can't
以他们无法做到的方式对事物做出反应
in a static game it produces new
在静态游戏中，它会产生新的
equilibria in the game folk theorems
博弈定理中的均衡
partly referring to the fact that these
部分是指这些
were
是
known for a long time in kind of
长期以来以
folklore and game theory before they
民俗学和博弈论
were actually written down
实际上被写下来
there's many equilibria in these things
这些东西之间有很多平衡
and they're based on on key ingredients
它们基于关键成分
having observation of what other players
观察其他玩家
do and being able to react to that and
能够并且能够对此做出反应
having sufficient value in the future
将来有足够的价值
either by limit of the means which is an
要么通过手段限制
extreme value or high enough discount
极高价值或足够高的折扣
factors so that players really care
使玩家真正关心的因素
about the future now repeated games have
关于未来现在重复的游戏有
actually been a fairly active area of
实际上是一个相当活跃的领域
research recently there's a lot of other
最近的研究还有很多其他的
interesting questions on these what
关于这些有趣的问题是什么
happens if you don't always see what
如果您不总是看到什么就会发生
other players do you only see sometimes
其他玩家您有时只会看到
there's some noises and things what
有一些噪音和其他东西
happens if there's uncertain payoffs
如果不确定的回报会发生
over time there are payoffs are varying
随着时间的流逝，收益是不同的
there's a whole series of issues there
那里有一系列的问题
there's also issues about things like
还有一些类似的问题
renegotiation so you know the logic here
重新谈判，所以你知道这里的逻辑
has been okay if if we anybody ever
如果我们有人曾经一直没事
deviates then we go to a bad equilibrium
偏离然后我们达到一个糟糕的平衡
forever after so suppose that happens
如此假设之后永远
somebody deviates and then we you know
有人偏离，然后我们知道
after about a few periods we say well
大约过了一段时间后，我们说好了
this is kind of silly why are we why are
这有点傻，为什么我们为什么
we hurting ourselves let's go back to
我们伤害自己让我们回到
the original agreement let's forget
原始协议让我们忘记
about things by Ron's be bygones so we
关于罗恩（Ron）过去的事情，所以我们
can do better by just starting all over
可以从头开始做得更好
right okay well that's wonderful the
好吧，那太好了
difficulty is that if if we now believe
困难在于如果我们现在相信
that if we deviate eventually we're
如果我们最终偏离了我们
going to be forgiven then that changes
将被原谅，然后改变
the whole nature of the game and changes
游戏的整体性质和变化
the the the incentives at the beginning
一开始的激励措施
and so incorporating that kind of logic
所以结合了这种逻辑
is is quite complicated and another area
是相当复杂的另一个领域
of research and in these so repeated
研究，并在这些如此重复
games are very interesting they have
游戏非常有趣
lots of applications there's some
很多应用程序中有一些
interesting logic which comes out of
有趣的逻辑
them sometimes you can sustain
他们有时你可以维持
cooperation or better payoffs and you
合作或更好的回报，您
can in the static setting sometimes you
可以在静态设置中有时
can't and we've seen some of the
不能，我们已经看到了一些
features that affect that
影响那个的功能